crosscut.com 2019-09-13

# Privacy Policy | Crosscut

Cascade Public Media (“CPM”) is the legal name for the organization that includes KCTS Television (“KCTS 9”) and Crosscut. This Privacy Policy applies to the website (collectively the “Site”) of each CPM entity. 

CPM (collectively “CPM,” “Us” or “We”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our donors, members, viewers and site visitors (collectively “You,” “Your” or “Yours”). We value Your trust, which means that we will properly collect any personal information that You give Us, that We will only use it for the purposes for which it is collected and that We will dispose of it in a secure and timely manner when it is no longer needed. 

For purposes of this Policy “personal information” means Your name, acknowledgment name, financial information associated with payment for a product or donation, address, telephone number, fax number, email address and personal preferences You may designate when creating an account profile. Unless there is a specific legal requirement we do not collect Your Social Security Number. Personal information does not include “aggregate” information, which we collect automatically about the use of the websites. “Aggregate” information means collective data that relate to a group or category of website visitors, from which individual identities or characteristics have been removed. This Policy does not restrict or limit Our collection and use of aggregate information. 

This Privacy Policy applies to Your personal information whether you give it to Us by phone, mail, in person, over the internet through a personal computer, mobile device or other means. 

**PURPOSE FOR COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**

Personal information may be collected by CPM when You call Us, email Us, mail Us or visit Our websites in connection with the following: 

  * Contest or sweepstakes registration
  * Subscription registration for sites or services which require subscription (such as Our e-newsletters, event RSVPs, etc.)
  * Requests for donor information
  * E-commerce transactions
  * Donations of any kind

In addition, We may use Your personal information to: 

  * Distribute receipts and send You a “thank you” for donations
  * Inform You about upcoming fundraising and other activities You might be interested in
  * Internal analysis, such as research and analytics
  * Record-keeping
  * Reporting to applicable government agencies as required by law
  * Surveys, metrics and other analytical purposes
  * Other purposes related to fundraising operations

Anonymized donor information or donor comments may be used for promotional and fundraising activities. We may ask You during the donation process for Your consent to use Your name publicly in connection with Your donation. You can always refuse consent or let Us know that You do not wish to allow Us to use Your personal information as we describe in this section either by email at [CustomerService@KCTS9.org](mailto:customerservice@KCTS9.org) or over the phone when you call to donate. 

However, in some circumstances, opting out may prevent You from participating in activities for which personal information is needed, such as contests. If You want to remain completely anonymous You may still take advantage of the wealth of content available on Our site that does not require registration. 

Like many other nonprofits, CPM occasionally exchanges some of Our donors’ names and postal addresses with carefully selected educational, cultural, health, and social service organizations in order to reach more potential supporters of Our organization in a cost-effective manner. We allow those organizations to mail CPM donors only once after which they must destroy Our donors’ information. CPM does not exchange email addresses or phone numbers. CPM may also disclose some personal information to carefully screened third-party service providers such as mailing houses and fundraising organizations. We may contract with them for the limited purpose of assisting Us with marketing and promotional activities. We carefully monitor their use of Your personal information and require them to adhere to this Policy. 

**CONSENT TO COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You understand the purposes for which Your personal information may be collected and You voluntarily consent to its collection, use or disclosure by Us. You may withdraw Your consent or request a correction of Your personal information at any time by providing Us with thirty (30) days’ notice. Send this notice to Our Donor & Audience Relations Manager at [CustomerService@KCTS9.org](mailto:CustomerService@KCTS9.org); the Donor & Audience Relations Manager is Our contact person for purposes of addressing questions or comments about this Privacy Policy. 

**USE OF FINANCIAL INFORMATION**

You may use a credit card, EFT/ACH information, or check when making a donation to CPM or making a purchase. All information from financial transactions made through a CPM website is stored and served from a secure server. This means that each page You view on Our website and any financial information You submit is encrypted on its way between Your computer and Ours. Even in the highly unlikely event that Your transmission is intercepted, the data may not be usable by a third party. If You send Us a check, the financial information on it may be entered into the same secure computer system. 

We take reasonable measures to protect Your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Our website host provides a continuous set of security updates, and monitors to address known security issues, consistent with industry standards. All of Our employees with access to the personal information You provide to Us through the websites or through any other means are bound by a confidentiality agreement prohibiting the unauthorized disclosure and/or use of Your personal information. 

Please be aware, however, that despite Our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. To mitigate this risk, You should (a) use secure usernames and passwords and carefully protect them from disclosure; and (b) implement updated internet security and virus protection on Your computer. If You suspect that Your computer’s security or Your information has been compromised or Your password accessed or used by an unauthorized third party, please contact Us immediately to have Your password changed. 

If We become aware of a security systems breach, within seven (7) days We may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may post a notice through the website if a security breach occurs. We may also send an email to You at the email address you have provided to Us in these circumstances. Depending on where You live, You may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. We agree with the Fair Information Practice Principles of the Federal Trade Commission. Your credit card information will be used only for Your intended purpose — be it a donation or a purchase — and nothing else. 

CPM has no control over other sites that are linked to Ours and we cannot tell you how those sites will treat Your personal information. For all online financial transactions You make through organizations that link to Our site, be sure to review those organizations’ privacy policies. If You have any questions regarding how the organizations use Your personal information, please contact them directly. 

CPM will maintain Your financial information only as long as necessary to satisfy the purpose for which it was obtained or as legally required. Thereafter it will be destroyed via appropriate, secure methods. 

**OUR TRACKING AND USE OF COOKIES**

We use a standard feature of browser software called a cookie to help Us respond to the needs and preferences of visitors. A cookie assigns each visitor a unique code that resides on the visitor’s computer. We may use cookies to measure user traffic or obtain other analytics, to provide personalized services or to improve Our website’s functionality. 

You can prevent or delete Our cookies by adapting Your browser settings, but this can affect the functionality of the website. Section 22575 of the California Business & Professions Code requires website and online service operators to disclose whether they honor web browser “Do Not Track” settings. We support and honor “Do Not Track” web browser settings. 

**AUTHORIZED THIRD PARTIES**

We may use third-party service providers to place advertisements to market on sites across the internet. The third-party service providers may collect anonymous information about Your visits to one of Our websites and may use that information to target ads for products and services. They may collect web log data or place or recognize a unique cookie on Your browser to enable You to receive customized ads. No personally identifiable information is collected in this process. They do not know Your name, address, email address, phone number or any personally identifiable information. 

The NAI (Network Advertising Initiative) allows for the central opting out of all its members’ cookies from a single opt-out page. If you prefer not to receive relevant advertising on web pages or are concerned about third-party cookies served by networks, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). 

**DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**

We do not share the personal information provided or obtained through Our websites with third parties, except as described below and as otherwise specified in this Policy. We may share personal information as follows: 

  * With the third party or third parties that perform(s) maintenance and operation of Our websites on Our behalf. These parties are bound by a confidentiality agreement prohibiting the unauthorized disclosure and/or use of Your personal information;
  * With other third parties that perform services or functions on Our behalf, such as third-party providers that facilitate payment and completion of donations. We do not authorize such third parties to use Your personal information for any other purposes and they are bound by this Privacy Policy;
  * As we believe necessary to comply with laws, statutes, or regulations, and/or to enforce this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use and to protect Our rights and the rights of others;
  * As required by a court or government agency or to respond to a claim by You or a third party;
  * As part of a transfer of Our assets, for example in the event of a merger, acquisition, corporate change; and
  * As You may otherwise request or agree.

**CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION**

Some of our websites may present educational content for children. Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), We will not knowingly request or collect personal information from any child under age 13. If We learn that a user under 13 years of age has submitted personal information through or using one of Our websites We will take reasonable measures to delete such information from Our databases and not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required by law).   
Please visit <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html> for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children’s privacy online. 

If Your child submits stories, artwork, comments or anything else to Us which is to be posted at one of our websites We will first contact the parent for permission to use the submission. If permission is granted the child will be identified only by first name, age or grade level, city and state. 

Our websites may link to third-party sites and we are not responsible for the content or safety and privacy practices of those sites. Therefore We encourage adults and children to discuss these choices together before giving out any information at these outside sites. 

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Effective January 1, 2005, under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, if an individual who is a California resident has provided personal information to a business in connection with a business relationship that is primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, and if that business has within the immediately preceding calendar year disclosed such an individual’s personal information to a third party and knows or should have known that such third party used the information for its own direct marketing purposes, then that business is obligated to disclose in writing to such individual upon request, what personal information was shared and with whom it was shared. 

Any request for a disclosure required under this California law should be sent to Us via email to Our Donor & Audience Relations Manager at [CustomerService@KCTS9.org](mailto:customerservice@KCTS9.org). 

Please note that under this law, We are not required to respond to a customer’s request more than once in a calendar year, nor are We required to respond to any request that is not sent to the email address designated above. 

**INTERNATIONAL VISITORS**

The websites are hosted in and provided from the United States. If You use the websites from the European Union, Canada, or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring Your personal data to the United States and You consent to the transfer of Your personal data to the United States and the use of Your Personal Information, in accordance with this Policy.1

**TELL US WHAT YOU THINK**

Your comments and questions help Us serve you better and make Your visit a pleasant one. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this statement, please send them to Our Donor & Audience Relations Manager at [CustomerService@KCTS9.org](mailto:customerservice@KCTS9.org). Please note that We may be required to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case We will comply with Your deletion request only after We have fulfilled such requirements). When We delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in Our archives. 

We may make periodic changes to add, remove, or modify portions of this Policy at any time. This Policy was last updated in April 2019. Please check this page from time to time for any changes. 

_Last updated and effective as of: April 2019._

  1. This Privacy Policy is intended to comply with British Columbia’s Personal Information Protection Act and applicable U.S. state and federal law.
